

Robin Salih Axelsson

System .NET Developer

Profile

Location: Gothenburg, Sweden

Job Status: Open to work

Speciality: Unit testing, Advanced C#, DevOps/Scripting

Tech Stack: Azure, React, C# .NET, MS SQL Server

Education: .NET Developer vocational degree, Teknikhögskolan (see courses)

Said about me: "He can solve any coding problem in this company"

Hobbies: Sail Racing, Gym, Coding, Brazilian Jiu Jitsu

Introduction

I am a .NET developer from Gothenburg who never stops learning. Before the covid pandemic I worked as a Design Engineer in the Gothenburg's automotive industry but when I discovered my talent and passion for writing code I changed my career to fully commit to Software Engineering.

I am a meticulous coder who values well-abstracted, simple code that is easy to test, maintain, and understand. I always have a programming project in mind - idées and solutions come to me around the clock. I actively seek knowledge from the necessary resources, including source code, decompiled code, programming books, AI tools, the web, online courses, and more.

I have developed a strong mental game through my years in competitive sailing, along with endless energy and stamina for problem-solving. In a team setting, I work autonomously, take initiative, and am not afraid to ask questions or learn from those around me.

Skill Assessment

.NET	****
ASP.NET	****
Azure App Service	***
Azure Blob Storage	***
Azure Cosmos DB	***
Azure DevOps	****
Azure Functions	***
Bash	***
Burp Suite	***
С	****
C#	****
Docker	****
Entity Framework	****
Express.js	***
Git	****
GitHub Actions	****
JavaScript	****
Linux	***

Experience

Software Engineer - Bokio, Gothenburg, April 2024 - October 2024

- Part of a fintech SaaS company building a book keeping application for the swedish market
- Tech-stack: Azure App Service -> React -> ASP.NET -> MS SQL Server
- Working in a self organizing .NET Platform team of 5 developers
- Developing backend login security features, secure file uploading, rest api integrations and logging to Azure Application Insights
- Tech: ASP.NET, Entity Framework Core, MS SQL Server, Azure, REST-API

System Developer - Iver Sverige, Gothenburg, Feb 2023 - April 2024

- Collaborated in the Team "Time & People" a SCRUM team of 3 developers
- · Participating in developing and designing end to end features in the same room as the business
- Maintaining and developing in a hugh code base (more then 3.3 million lines of code)
- Designing and developing business automation features
- Team responsible for git management and hot fixes in the Azure DevOps Pipeline
- · Implementing new business logic and domain logic
- Tech: Microsoft WPF, .NET, ASP.NET, NHibernate, MS SQL Server, Azure, REST-API

Full Stack Cloud Developer Consultant - Software by Quokka/Volvo Cars, Gothenburg Feb 2022 - Feb 2023

- Collaborated in a SCRUM team of 4 developers within under SAFE
- Participating in designing a new integration application for data extraction
- Responsible for designing a unit testing base and postman testing
- Driving refactoring and applying OOD practices
- Tech: .NET, ASP.NET, SystemWeaverApi, REST-API, SQL-lite, X-Unit, Azure

Backend Developer Internship - Nexer Group, Gothenburg Okt 2021 - Dec 2021

- Collaborated in an inhouse SCRUM Team within a micro service architecture.
- Responsible for the redesign/remake of an ASP.NET REST API.
- Tech stack: Angular/Graph QL/ASP.NET/Azure Storage

Design Engineer - CEVT (China Euro Vehicle Company), Gothenburg Feb 2020 - May 2020

- Responsible for the design of sheet metal Console in the fuel system of the CMA platform (Volvo XC40, Lynk&co: 01, 02, 03).
- Assisting System Engineers with management of CAD-parts in the PLM system Siemens TeamCenter.
- · Driving communication with interfaceing Chineese team.
- Tech: PLM Siemens TeamCenter, Catia V5

Design Engineer Internship - CEVT (China Euro Vehicle Company), Gothenburg Feb 2019 - May 2019

- Responsible for redesigning and tolerancing a lock-unit housing in injection molded plastic for Lync & Co 01 (2021) model. The goal was to pass the Euro NCAP impact demands of 2020 and the work was made as a part of the Interior Design Team.
- Tech: Catia V5

Highlighted Projects

Exchange Rates Fetcher SOAP to REST - Bokio

Bokio is a bookkeeping web app targeting big and small companies on the Swedish market. Bokio has some banking features that rely on having up-to-date exchange rates from the Swedish currency. The problem was that our current implimentation SOAP was soon end of life and will be replaced by a REST API (that was not mapped one to one). I wrote a custom http client integration that fetched exchange rate data on a given time every day to sync it to a SQL database. I also implemented the endpoints for the frontend and a fallback to directly call the Web API directly if the server sync was down.

C#, Azure, ASP.NET, Entity Framework, T-SQL, DefaultHttpClientFactory, SocketsHttpHandler

Timer and Worker Module in Cendot by Iver 1998-Present - Iver Sverige

Cendot is a monolithic desktop app that is distributed on Citrix servers to the Iver Employees. Cendots architecture is of MVVM design and is all written in C#. The core domain logic is also used in company owned apps as dll:s or nugets in web apps, worker services and REST API:s. As a diverse IT-Service company with its own self made business eco-system (Cendot) and its own development appartment, Iver process owners have an intimate connection with our developer team. Together we design and discuss new features that automate processes, simplifys time reporting, pricing and invoicing. We also enable new pricing models and business concepts.

C#, Microsoft WPF, T-SQL, NHibernate, Citrix, Rest-API, Azure DevOps, Azure Application Insights

Software Update Management System (SUMS) - Data Summery Service - Volvo Cars

This applications purpose is to generate Software Update Management System (SUMS) traceability documents for car variant certification. This is to be able to oblige with stricter EU and other regulations for modern cars. With the Software-PLM platform SystemWeaver as source for data we designed a core app that integrates with the SystemWeaver nuget API and collects the relevant data following a preprogrammed set of extensive business rules (and outputs a different readable documents).

My main contribution was development of the applications testing projects (integration and unit test), dependency management, driving code refactoring and code design.

C#, X-Unit, Microsoft Dependency Injection, ASP.NET Web API, PowerShell, AzureDevOps, SystemWeaver, Jira, SQL-lite

BoostApp PX - ASP.NET Reverse Proxy REST API for company time reports - Nexer Group

Responsible for building a reverse Proxy API (ASP.NET) in a micro service architecture within a inhouse SCRUM Team. Further responsible for implementing OAuth 2.0 (Microsoft Identity Platform, AD), CI/CD with Azure DevOps and Docker, integration testing and scripting with Postman.

C#, ASP.NET Web API, Microsoft Identity Server, Azure DevOps, Docker, HttpClient, Postman, Microsoft Dependency Injection

Ludo V2 Online - .NET multiplayer SignalR Game Engine and Platform - Teknikhögskolan

Responsible for building a Fullstack ASP.NET Web, Ludo Board Game Platform. Implementations: SQL server with Entity Framework for user and game data, email login, email game invitations, SignalR interactive gaming, token and cookie identification, multiple game rooms, AI players and server side logic. To enable multiple game rooms every game room has its own instance of an game engine IOC container. The project was developed in a two man team.

C#, ASP.NET, SignalR, Entity-Framework, JWT, Cookies, Html, JavaScript, CSS, GitHub, Microsoft Dependency Injection

Education

.NET Developer Voccational Degree (see courses) - Teknikhögskolan, 2020 - 2022

CAD-Engineer - Mechanical Design Voccational Degree - YRGO Lindholmen, 2017 - 2019

Psychologist: Sports Programme - Umeå University, 2012 - 2013

Basics of Psychology - Gothenburg University, 2011 - 2012

High School Diploma in Science & Sail Racing Lerums Gymnasium 2007 - 2011

Contact

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin,com/in/axelsson-robin</u>

GitHub: <u>github.com/robinaxelsson</u> (demo on request)

Site: <u>salihaxelsson.com</u>

Latest CV: salihaxelsson.com/cv